Visionary. Billionaire. Fraud?
The Inventor: Out for Blood in Silicon Valley is a
documentary film directed by Alex Gibney.
With a magical new invention that promised to revolutionize blood testing, Elizabeth Holmes
became the world’s youngest self-made billionaire, heralded as the next Steve Jobs.
Then, overnight, her 10-billion-dollar company dissolved.
The rise and fall of Theranos is a window into the psychology of fraud.
Self - CEO and Founder of Theranos (archive
footage), played by Elizabeth Holmes.
Self - Narrator / Interviewer, played by Alex Gibney.
Self - Behavioral Economist, played by Dan Ariely.
Self - Fortune, played by Roger Parloff.
Self - The New Yorker, played by Ken Auletta.
Self - Lab Associate, played by Erika Cheung.
The Inventor: Out for Blood in Silicon Valley is a 2019 American
documentary film, directed and produced by Alex Gibney.
The film revolves around Elizabeth Holmes and her former company Theranos.
It is considered a companion piece to the book, Bad Blood:
Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup.
The Inventor had its world premiere at the Sundance
Film Festival on January 24, 2019.
It was produced by HBO Documentary Films and Jigsaw Productions with a television
premiere on March 18, 2019, on HBO as well as its streaming platforms.
The film explores themes of technology, fraud, business,
medical research, health documentary.